Guilherme Gomes de Lucas

Berlin, Germany guilhermedelucas@yahoo.com







www.linkedin.com/in/ guilhermegomesdelucas

Profile

Recently I complete a Full Stack study program at a coding bootcamp where I developed Javascript, Html, CSS, Jquery, Ajax, and React skills. I have knowledge s to work with Single Page Applications and REST applications and experience of building responsive website with Bootstrap or just with Javascript, CSS and Html. The last months I've being studying and building applications with React and Redux, I create my own boilerplate with babel and web pack to develop React apps with Node server. For the backend I have ability to develop servers with Node.js and Express, and use PostgresSQL or MongoDB databases. I appreciate Test Driven Development, and can create tests unity using Jest or Mocha.

My strong skills are faster learner, a great sense of troubleshooting, and handle deadlines and pressure situations. I bring from my past working experiences designing skills, inherited by working as design graphics freelance since 2007 and a commercial experience as a editorial design.

Skills

Technologies: Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS3, Angular.js, React, Redux, PostgresSQL, MongoDb Express, Node.js, Atom, Git, Mocha, Jest, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustrator. Concetps: Agile - Scrum. Languages: English, proficient. Portuguese, native.

Experience

Fullstack Developer, SPICED Academy; Berlin – 10/2016 - 02/2017

On SPICED Academy bootcamp I could immerse on web development with Javascript using technologies as HTML5, CSS3, React, Angular, Node, Express, Handlebars, jQuery, Git, NPM, PostgresSQL, MongoDB and several other frameworks and libraries like Bootstrap and Semantic-UI. I have been introduced to Agile Scrum, Test Driven Development (TDD) and Unity Testing.

Editorial Designer / Designer Graphic, Correio Mariliense; Marília, Brazil - 09/2007 - 02/2013

Creativity and fast production were the key for my success on this periodic newspaper.

Hired for the first work team of the periodic, responsible for create an template for the newspaper, and supervise the designers team to follow the newspaper design standards.

Education

SPICED Academy, Berlin, Germany – Full-stack developer (Oct 2016 - current)
Unimar, Marília, Brazil – Civil Engineer Bachelor (2011 - 2015)

LINIVEM Marília, Brazil – Post-Graduated – Marketing (2007 - 2008)

UNIVEM, Marília, Brazil - Post-Graduated - Marketing (2007 - 2008) UNIVEM, Marília, Brazil - Designer Graphic Technician (2005 - 2007)

Projects

https://github.com/guilhermedelucas/guilhermedelucas-react-redux-boilerplate - My personal boilerplate setting to work with react. Ready to work on develop mode and deploy in production. www.ventronearquitetura.com.br - Website for one Brazilian Architect https://gobackfilms-nodljbzuht.now.sh - (Under construction) - Website for a Film Producer Company http://smalltalkspiced.herokuapp.com/ - Website like Reddit developed on the Bootcamp program http://spiced-projects-guilherme.herokuapp.com/ - Page containing all exercises developed on the Bootcamp.